<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-02T09:42:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">jremillard.com</title><subtitle>A small website to write about things I'm learning, post my thoughts to forget later, things to teach that may be useful, and possible to post projects.
</subtitle><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Time to revisit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/06/time-to-revisit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time to revisit" /><published>2021-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/06/time-to-revisit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/06/time-to-revisit.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been some time since I’ve wrote an article, I tried to get myself to write one a few times but never could. It felt like I had to derive what I had and made it look like it’s purpose was to get jobs or money, something of value instead of having personal value. I didn’t want to move away from that, the simplicity of my blog is exactly what I like. It’s Ruby Jekyll with Markdown posts that get stored on GitHub. There is no search bar, just pagination and simple colors. To move away and to “update” it would make it feel like it would be the death of my intention of this site from the start. It is a place for me to learn and reflect back on what I thought was worthy and purpose later write about things that I thought were not worthy but was.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s been some time since I’ve wrote an article, I tried to get myself to write one a few times but never could. It felt like I had to derive what I had and made it look like it’s purpose was to get jobs or money, something of value instead of having personal value. I didn’t want to move away from that, the simplicity of my blog is exactly what I like. It’s Ruby Jekyll with Markdown posts that get stored on GitHub. There is no search bar, just pagination and simple colors. To move away and to “update” it would make it feel like it would be the death of my intention of this site from the start. It is a place for me to learn and reflect back on what I thought was worthy and purpose later write about things that I thought were not worthy but was.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project to move away from Firebase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/12/Project-to-move-away-from-Firebase.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project to move away from Firebase" /><published>2020-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/12/Project-to-move-away-from-Firebase</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/12/Project-to-move-away-from-Firebase.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-website-setup-overall&quot;&gt;The website setup overall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up this website with wanting to integrate CI/CD without too much of a reason other than exposure. I had the student account from Travis CI. Also, I wanted to have HTTPS set up, all in all, this just added additional overhead but the experience was fun. Knowing a commit did a lot behind the scenes to get it to the website. But, it’s been awhile and it’s time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cost&quot;&gt;Cost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firebase costs money although it’s not expensive. The horror stories from many founders on beind nearly bankrupt because of the intense Firebase cost to host was something that’s made me want to lean away from, especially since there is free options like GitHub pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cicd-unnecessary-work&quot;&gt;CI/CD unnecessary work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As cool as it is to use CI/CD, for a blog purpose based on simplicity is just not necessary. I originally intended this website to eventually grow into sharing projects. Upon thinking about it, sharing projects on a personal website makes no sense, at least in the sense of hosting. Why not keep it simple, like on GitHub with README’s?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-moving-forward&quot;&gt;Project moving forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple. Move off of Firebase and Travis CI to GitHub pages. Might as well as it: free hosting and route my domain to GitHub. Eh, it’s late and I’ve had a few truly’s. Let the idea’s flow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-will-personal-projects-go&quot;&gt;Where will personal projects go?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a new site that I want to work on call esseredesigns.com. I plan to put all my creative itches there and any software projects in GitHub. Eventually with this blog I’d like implement data tables and be able to search for blogs. We will see! Kind of tedious work when you’re busy but you know what, nothing a few sips of whisky can’t solve!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">The website setup overall I set up this website with wanting to integrate CI/CD without too much of a reason other than exposure. I had the student account from Travis CI. Also, I wanted to have HTTPS set up, all in all, this just added additional overhead but the experience was fun. Knowing a commit did a lot behind the scenes to get it to the website. But, it’s been awhile and it’s time to move on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basic Investing For Beginners</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/22/Basic-Investing-For-Beginners.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basic Investing For Beginners" /><published>2020-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/22/Basic-Investing-For-Beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/22/Basic-Investing-For-Beginners.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-investing&quot;&gt;What is investing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of resources on what is investing: vehicles such as real estate, stock market, bonds, loans, etc. Plethora of content to understand the general outlets of investing. Many articles do not cover the important topic of investing in of itself besides “make more money by using your money.” In reality, look to the ones that are in the real investing game. Not your grandparents or parents, in fact they may not even be in the stock market! Investing is this: there is a risk but what you are doing is helping a company or something grow into something real. Invest in what you believe with understanding of that field and what it is that you’re putting your money in. Think of it like this: you can look at the numbers all you want and perhaps long game you will win, but if you’re in the short term then there are few things you need to do which I will cover briefly both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;short-term&quot;&gt;Short term&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to investing, the key is what is your goal. When you hear the term, you probably think of money, economy, and stocks. Frankly, that’s a façade rather a term with primary usage for that field. I was given a piece of advice which was invest in yourself, as you are the greatest asset. This can be however you may view as beneficial for yourself. Courses for a certificate, exercising, reading self-help books, whatever it may be, ensure it helps you become the best possible you that you want to be. These can be done in quick spikes, however, I do not believe there is such a thing as true short term investing. Everything is a drop in the bucket to fill it up, it’s when that investing for that portion ends which can be classified as an arbitrary short term method of investing. Key component is reflection and this goes for both methods. Reflect, reflect, reflect. The trajectory, is it accurate? Are you on par? Is the trajectory in the wrong directory? Do I need to take a couple steps back to take a few steps forward or side step laterally? The questions you ask need to be from you: observe others and create your own fortifying and beneficial questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;long-term&quot;&gt;Long term&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s money, exercising, sport, or academics, what it is, you’re in there for long haul. Understand there will be dips, look at any long term stock and you will see highs and lows but always increases over time. That is the goal here and it is applicable to just about anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short article yes, perhaps not the topic you were expecting, but I want to share and help spread that the idea and concept of investing goes beyond money. You can throw your money in an ETF or index fund with high chances that you’ll do fine. But not everyone decides to take a few days of the year to read, write, and make themselves proud.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">What is investing? There are tons of resources on what is investing: vehicles such as real estate, stock market, bonds, loans, etc. Plethora of content to understand the general outlets of investing. Many articles do not cover the important topic of investing in of itself besides “make more money by using your money.” In reality, look to the ones that are in the real investing game. Not your grandparents or parents, in fact they may not even be in the stock market! Investing is this: there is a risk but what you are doing is helping a company or something grow into something real. Invest in what you believe with understanding of that field and what it is that you’re putting your money in. Think of it like this: you can look at the numbers all you want and perhaps long game you will win, but if you’re in the short term then there are few things you need to do which I will cover briefly both.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hinting Indexes in MySQL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/21/hinting-indexes-in-mysql.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hinting Indexes in MySQL" /><published>2020-11-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/21/hinting-indexes-in-mysql</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/21/hinting-indexes-in-mysql.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;mysql-itself&quot;&gt;MySQL itself&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, MySQL is a solid and if not the most capable relational database. Quite the broad statement but it’s true to an extent. It does have limitations and should not be treated as a key / value database as well as data warehouse. It is a relational database, great for decent scaling with capabilities of impressive IOPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;onto-the-issue&quot;&gt;Onto the issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, developers do not and personally should not understand the inner workings of MySQL. However, if advised and treated as a non-relational database then that is where the issue comes into play. Allowing customers to abuse a feature that was briefly introduced as a professional services product due to a request of a high MRR customers. To reiterate and be clear, &lt;em&gt;this has no impact, no representation of my work/day job&lt;/em&gt;. Now, onto the issue. The misunderstanding and perhaps politics in play cause headaches later. When clustered indexs are in, unfortunately there are things in MySQL related to SQL that the MySQL optimizer may think it is indeed doing the best possible query to the database. However, there are cases where lack of indexes rather incorrect index may cause overflow of searched an extra partition or however many extra rows, decreasing overall effiency and response times. How to fix this? To note: I said hint. In the end, the optimizer decides what it wants to do. But with SQL you can either force or ask the optimizer to use a specific index instead of a range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;select * from &lt;em&gt;table&lt;/em&gt; use index (idx);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple yeah? Reiterate: this is hinting. You could force but that may have unintentional consequences. Always refer to the documentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/optimizer-hints.html&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/index-hints.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one part in a very complicated table of optimization. Keep in mind there is only so much you can do and constantly tuning the database without the need may not be a good approach in keeping high availability and robustness.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">MySQL itself Look, MySQL is a solid and if not the most capable relational database. Quite the broad statement but it’s true to an extent. It does have limitations and should not be treated as a key / value database as well as data warehouse. It is a relational database, great for decent scaling with capabilities of impressive IOPS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Importance of Recharging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/20/Importance-of-recharging.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Importance of Recharging" /><published>2020-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/20/Importance-of-recharging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/20/Importance-of-recharging.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;recharging&quot;&gt;Recharging&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in awhile, every engineer will encounter a time of fatigue. However, the difference between a junior and more experience engineer is noticing onset fatigue. It is important to understand your symptoms of fatigue, mainly understanding why the business value here is incredible. Allowing emplyoees to continue to work regardless of energy levels will the end produce poor quality work leading to a spiral downpour of systems lacking reliability and increase oversight, therefore downtimes and further fatigue. Allowing yourself time to recharge encompasses wholly the emotional intelligence by identifying &lt;em&gt;BEFORE&lt;/em&gt; it onsets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-some-symptoms-rather-how-to-identify&quot;&gt;What are some symptoms? Rather, how to identify?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without looking online for true symptoms, I’d rather talk about myself since it is my opinion therefore does not require any kind of scientific study background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-step-one&quot;&gt;Key step one&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trial and error has been one of my strong suites. Since learning web development back in when I was 12, the resources for online learning was lacking. W3schools and perhaps random forums where caveats were pointed out by experience developers. I took that without documenting it myself and somehow took away a decent chunk of knowledge. So in this case, step one is persistence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-step-two&quot;&gt;Key step two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening. We speak too much, we talk to much. “How to win friends and influence people” by Dale Carnegie highlights key components in building modular relationships is &lt;em&gt;LISTENING&lt;/em&gt;. Not only that, but understand. Truly map it out. Listen to your body. Mentally, emotionally, physically, sleep patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-step-three&quot;&gt;Key step three&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify your refreshing moments. Is it mountain biking? Training for a marathon? Racing? Making a money? Key takeaway is sitting and watching Netflix isn’t the refreshing you may need. Humans are naturally made to be active. Find something to keep yourself busy but keep yourself away from repetitive topic/area of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-step-four&quot;&gt;Key step four&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement a plan. Exactly where is the limit, write that down. Convey it, express it, explain the benefits and utilize CAVE from the previous post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">Recharging Every once in awhile, every engineer will encounter a time of fatigue. However, the difference between a junior and more experience engineer is noticing onset fatigue. It is important to understand your symptoms of fatigue, mainly understanding why the business value here is incredible. Allowing emplyoees to continue to work regardless of energy levels will the end produce poor quality work leading to a spiral downpour of systems lacking reliability and increase oversight, therefore downtimes and further fatigue. Allowing yourself time to recharge encompasses wholly the emotional intelligence by identifying BEFORE it onsets.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UI Protect</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/19/ui-protect.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UI Protect" /><published>2020-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/19/ui-protect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/19/ui-protect.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ubiquiti&quot;&gt;Ubiquiti&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fascinated with the products of Ubiquiti. The capabilities out of the box has been on point with easy home network setup for those with some knowledge. Customizable in some sense to get the job done that I want it too. Obviously other aspects needed like LAN wide adblocker and dnsmasq domain to access servers do not come out of the box with perhaps the most useful machine UI has released, Ubiquiti Dream Machine Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love this machine, creating essentially a VPN to UI’s cloud where accessible software within UDMPro is seamless in aspects. I don’t have to open up my firewall so I can ssh in with high latency with some failures based on my raspberry pi’s VPN. That has been set aside and no longer is necessary. As for integration with the other products, it’s overall solid. Of course bugs appear here and there, especially graphical glitches due to outsourcing and cutting costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;laying-down-cable&quot;&gt;Laying down cable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most arduous task with setting up a UI home network is cabling. It’s all PoE or PnPPoE which can make it difficult because screw injectors. Routing cable in a home where that is non-existant is a pain, drilling holes left and right simply because the house is just too old is non-sense grunt work but satisfying. One thing to note, as useful as the graphs may be with the network software with UI, there are graphical glitches with traffic graphs specific to various devices’. Overall, seamless and effective. I do recommend setting up at least a pi-hole to help block advertisement and use the dnsmasq out of the box that come with it. Raspberry is so cheap, PoE for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">Ubiquiti I’ve been fascinated with the products of Ubiquiti. The capabilities out of the box has been on point with easy home network setup for those with some knowledge. Customizable in some sense to get the job done that I want it too. Obviously other aspects needed like LAN wide adblocker and dnsmasq domain to access servers do not come out of the box with perhaps the most useful machine UI has released, Ubiquiti Dream Machine Pro.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Opportunities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/18/Opportunities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opportunities" /><published>2020-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/18/Opportunities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/18/Opportunities.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-it&quot;&gt;What is it&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficult part when learning these ‘engineering manager’ terminology/phisolophy is realistically approaching a subordinate, rather, them approaching you with you setting them up to think they are. Instead of focusing on nuances, the important aspect as an manager is providing opportunities to younger engineers for them to take or not, tasking opportunities to senior engineers, then the middle ground where it’s a slight mix of both. A stronger version of providing opportunities and little on the plate of tasking opportunities. How the maximise is the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problem-identification&quot;&gt;Problem identification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to sit back, at least for me, and identify a lot of problems. I approach the system with the customer mindset learned from entrepreneur days; what exactly is it that would attract ‘me’ as a customer? Seamless/frictionless, intuitive, robustness, etc. The importance varies greatly among peoples experience and goal: straightforward or experience. It’s finding the middle ground with the business value in mindset that is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wordage&quot;&gt;Wordage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wording your approach is key in moving forward with a solution. Due dilligence needs to be done before laying it on the table but first, getting the person in charge on board. Use their method of incentives against them, tailer it to their ears. As stupid is it may be in this current economy, the concept of tailering each resume for a job is blasphemy. You have no reference on who is looking at the resume as if they always are. You can get a general gist of the ‘mission’ of a company but frankly it’s generic and broad corporate linguistics that realistically attract other businesses. One big hustle. Not to stray away but understand words are powerful, get the gist across in the tailored method.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">What is it The difficult part when learning these ‘engineering manager’ terminology/phisolophy is realistically approaching a subordinate, rather, them approaching you with you setting them up to think they are. Instead of focusing on nuances, the important aspect as an manager is providing opportunities to younger engineers for them to take or not, tasking opportunities to senior engineers, then the middle ground where it’s a slight mix of both. A stronger version of providing opportunities and little on the plate of tasking opportunities. How the maximise is the question.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CAVE</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/02/CAVE.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CAVE" /><published>2020-11-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/02/CAVE</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/02/CAVE.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a little over a year and a half since I joined SendGrid. I was onboarded a junior database engineer with the primary goal to learn as much as possible, do some grunt work, and take some load off of the principal and senior engineer. Especially as there was plans to ramp up work off of a contractor to an inside team. That is what I was hired on for. However, if you know me in a personal sense, I learn quickly by watching but it is not how I deeply learn. I am able to mimick decently, perhaps able to perhaps in lamence capabilities right off the start with a learning and improvement curve as if its log base 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-curve&quot;&gt;Learning curve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning the basics was no problem, in fact, I would not have considered myself a “junior” in the terms of fresh out of college. Technology has been a fasicnation and passion of mine for some time, realistically kicking it in to high gear as of 2017. Really delving into things and really getting things done, instead of knowing surface level of many different things and can kind of get things done. This, albeit junior-esque, really thrusted me past that junior expectation that was expected of me. Linux and SQL, programming and bash, etc. I proved I was not a junior and it took some time to convince. However, one thing that was acknowledged was my hunger to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rdbms&quot;&gt;RDBMS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relational databases are quite complex. When thrown into a business production environment where millions of queries are being run with hundreds to thousands of gigabytes of data, things get complicated. There are general rights-wrongs in use cases, however when it comes to finite things like tuning configurations, it’s a right and/or wrong statement. It’s a “yes perhaps, maybe, possibly”, where uncertainty is strong. Soft skills though can easily be mimicked based on observation of others. A “senior/staff” engineer mostly does engineering work, beyond that? Principle and whatnot, thats where broad-term behavior is expected. Convincing other teams, influencing team/department/other team decisions, where putting-the-foot down is a responsibility. Of course this is generalizing but my overall gist is the soft skills required to complete thos responsibilities is one that flows with me decently. Observation and mimicking only goes so far however it is key to boost you in that area. I asked the VP of engineering once why he chose to go into management rather than stay an engineer. His answer was that people are more complicated to manage than software. You could argue against this with a database and frankly, the typical dba response of “yes well no, maybe, possibly” would kick in. Too many caveats. Management is a path I was go into, but I don’t want to just go into it, I want to go into it with the right mindset and skillset. Soft skills is a must to succeed and for your team to succeed. Naturally, asking questions about that was much easier than MySQL. Simply because you can look up the documentation compared to situational. If that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, one thing I learned recently is using, arguably, a social engineering form to move up in the ladder. When in a corporate structure, each person had their responsibilities and incentives. The higher you go, incentives get stronger and stronger. That is something you can use. Say, the manager of your team’s job is to help you succeed, get projects done, and answer any questions you have and draw the line. This may be their responsibilities but their incentives would be to deliver projects with quality, quantity, and continue to grow strong engineers, gate the bad decisions and offer good decisions consulted by the team, to their manager but in this case lets say director. Now the director, perhaps the job is about seeing a 2 year plan in the works to be smooth, as well as ensure the department is in budget, automate or improve areas to be more efficient, etc. Save the company money and produce money at a low level. Their incentive really is to perhaps their VP or GM to deliver those projects with lower costs and increased revenue within 1-2-3 year plans. Great, now we’re at the VP. VP in this case lets say reports to the CTO whom CTO reports to COO and COO reports to CEO. The critical difference here that is relevant is the VP’s job is to make sure the business or product grows at an expected YoY rate, along those lines. The CTO/COO perhaps is to ensure the product really makes money, asking tough questions ruthlessly. However, that is not too important in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall position in utilizing “social engineering” in a ladder listed above is finding the incentives and being able to solve it up until its relevancy. As an engineer, as great as it may be, the problems of a CTO are vastly different then the problems I encounter. The relevancy is the point where any problem you solve wouldn’t necessary “solve” the CTO/COO/CEO’s problem. However, going 2 above may be the sweet spot, 3 if you can. We know the incentives of our manager and their boss (director). Let’s say a project comes in from up above saying we need to move a database cluster to AWS Aurora. If I was a junior engineer, my mindset would be “ok let’s see how to do that”. A senior engineer’s mindset would see problems in going from Point A to Point B. A principle’s mindset would see long-term problems. Of course those two mindsets can blend and it’s not a strict layout. There is where my soft skills improvement could kick in along with observations. I’ve sat back and listened enough to understand there is a method to bite back on a bad idea that is being asked of the team. To note, there is a line where simply no matter what you can say, it’ll happen. However, many cases you can make a case that would revert that idea. Much of this could be covered in “How to win friends and influence people” to a point, but the case I am making here to learning as an engineer to inform my manager the negatives of a project and how to give them ammunition to fight the director. In hopes of the director understanding the consequences and goes from there. The question I first asked myself is the business value. Does this increase or decrease business value? The broadness can be applied in real dollars to engineer time, consequence of failing or lack of support to ensure a solid transition. In a solid engineering environment there is likely a process already in place to help prevent these kind of decisions. But I wanted to do my own and no doubt someday this will be applicable once I become a manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cost
Analysis
Value
Explain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CAVE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple and perhaps can be redundant, but my overall point is the redundancy in this acronym. Cost-analysis is used frequently together, which could blend in with value but I would argue they can be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cost: Real dollars. How much will this cost? Engineer’s time, L&amp;amp;E, maintanance, anything that you can tie dollars too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysis: Point A to Point B, variables, caveats, roadblocks, dependencies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Value: What does this bring to the business? Could be profits, engineers time, notority, requested feature, PR, whatever it may be. Just what does it bring to the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain: This is key. You can throw numbers and let them speak for themselves but often that doesn’t really get the homerun. It’s the delivery tailed to the incentive of whom you are speaking too. What is it that they need to deliver and how would or wouldn’t this idea/project fulfill those incentives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this isn’t applicable in all cases and there are many processes in place to fulfill exactly this acronym, but hardly do I see anyone putting this in simple adjectives/nouns/verbs that could be self-explanatory at the very least and accessible. The goal here is engineering is beyond being able to do or understand the technical problem, but also the business problem. That puts you a step above.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">Introduction It has been a little over a year and a half since I joined SendGrid. I was onboarded a junior database engineer with the primary goal to learn as much as possible, do some grunt work, and take some load off of the principal and senior engineer. Especially as there was plans to ramp up work off of a contractor to an inside team. That is what I was hired on for. However, if you know me in a personal sense, I learn quickly by watching but it is not how I deeply learn. I am able to mimick decently, perhaps able to perhaps in lamence capabilities right off the start with a learning and improvement curve as if its log base 2.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Orchestrator unable to install on Raspberry Pi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/08/Orchestrator-unable-to-install-on-Raspberry-Pi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orchestrator unable to install on Raspberry Pi" /><published>2020-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/08/Orchestrator-unable-to-install-on-Raspberry-Pi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/08/Orchestrator-unable-to-install-on-Raspberry-Pi.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;bummer&quot;&gt;Bummer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my latest venture of creating a home lab, one that somewhat would mimic that of production, Orchestrator was top of my list to view MySQL topologies purely. I have little hardware available to me but a plethora of Raspberry Pi’s. I figured that it would be made in good use especially since I installed a Pi hole. Installing Pi hole was easy and flawless, simply pointed my Ubiquiti Dream Machine Pro DHCP IP to the IP of the Pi hole &lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt; even using Pi hole’s dns server. That was the one thing that the Ubiquiti DMP really lacked, the capability of having a local domain name and accessing it via hostname instead of IP. Not only would this make orchestrator WILDLY uncomfortable to use if it’s just IP’s for discovery, but creating an endpoint with IP’s just isn’t feasible. And editing my /etc/hosts on every machine just seemed ridiculous, devices should use the routers DNS server. Fortunately Pi hole fixed that problem, easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;architecture&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not know this but Raspberry Pi’s are armhf architecture, not arm64. Originally, it didn’t make much sense since Raspbian is Debium linux distro based. Turns out, &lt;em&gt;armhf&lt;/em&gt; is the name given to a debian port for arm processors. So raspbian is unique in the sense of a rebuild of armhf in of itself to support the hardware that Raspberry Pi’s come with to work around floating point support. Now, that is according to the top Google result regarding armhf vs. arm. Below the answer is a comment that this difference goes even further. However, it’s not relevant anymore since 2015+ Debian armhf only works on newer Pi’s. But why is this an issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Orchestrator does NOT support this architecture and there isn’t anything I can do about it. It was quite the bummer indeed. There is one venture I have yet to continue to pursue but there IS support for armhf with docker. The possibility of having Orchestrator run in a container using a macvlan therefore has its own unique address which I can then map in Pi hole to a hostname seems like the best possibility granted that orchestrator itself does not use a lot of resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I get that running, that may be the first thing I share. Really could be a game changer in an environment where having one Orchestrator container per service that utilizes a solid MySQL topology would be nice. Given that each orchestrator instance uses an ACL therefore can be assigned the proper group for the development team to manage their own databases.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">Bummer In my latest venture of creating a home lab, one that somewhat would mimic that of production, Orchestrator was top of my list to view MySQL topologies purely. I have little hardware available to me but a plethora of Raspberry Pi’s. I figured that it would be made in good use especially since I installed a Pi hole. Installing Pi hole was easy and flawless, simply pointed my Ubiquiti Dream Machine Pro DHCP IP to the IP of the Pi hole AND even using Pi hole’s dns server. That was the one thing that the Ubiquiti DMP really lacked, the capability of having a local domain name and accessing it via hostname instead of IP. Not only would this make orchestrator WILDLY uncomfortable to use if it’s just IP’s for discovery, but creating an endpoint with IP’s just isn’t feasible. And editing my /etc/hosts on every machine just seemed ridiculous, devices should use the routers DNS server. Fortunately Pi hole fixed that problem, easily.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Home Lab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/05/home-lab.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home Lab" /><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/05/home-lab</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/05/home-lab.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;real-home-lab&quot;&gt;Real home lab&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen several posts on Hacker News regarding setting up a home lab. One thing that really itches is a standard definition of what a home lab is. Frankly, it’s too broad to have a set definition of ‘X’ amount switches, servers, and what you need to do with it. A home lab is the definition in of itself, it’s a lab. It’s a place to learn by trial and error, use new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;house&quot;&gt;House&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s about time but I finally got a house, now I can set up a real lab. Fortunately and unfortunately, the laundry room is an isolated room accessed via the garage, however, there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; cooling via vent from the AC, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; get this, a vent for heat to exhaust out of from the water heater. WOW! Holy grail of natural media room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up&quot;&gt;Setting up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fortunately had a mini server rack with a fully loaded Dell R710 and R620. Originally, I had Cisco L2 managed switches which I used as a unmanaged. I also was able to obtain netgear 4 drive NAS 1U server with 4 8TB Red WD’s. Using CAT5e cable I was able to reach near 500MB of transfer speed, making sharing files within the LAN quite quick. I had a Ubiquiti EdgeRouter with a bridged port to a Eero mesh network to allow WiFi and another port for hard wired devices like the servers and mini PC’s. I also set up the EdgeRouter’s built-in dnsmasq service to allow hostnames to be considered part of a local domain ‘myraidify.net’. This allowed the ability to create in-house pages like uptime (decouvrir) and seamless loadbalancing as managing DHCP ip’s is a big PITA in a LAN based environment. I however upgraded to use Ubiquiti AP’s in lieu of Eero’s as the eero’s were first generation before bought out by Amazon, thus the hardware as dying. I went overboard and got two UAC-AP-Pro’s in a 900 sqft apartment. Which if you know, can reach 400 sqft with 1GB+ 5Ghz and my apartment being mostly drywall. The frequencies did interfere often, soon after though I moved out of the apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-it-right&quot;&gt;Doing it right&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m blogging while running on little sleep and non-stop patching, scheduling, handling appointments, and planning equipment for my new house that I purchased in Austin so bare with me. Moving in, I already knew what I wanted: Ubiquiti network with 3rd party physical security system with remote monitoring. The latter that comes to mind with it’s geurilla marketing is: simplisafe. I was skeptical and wanted the ability to not have to pay for monitoring but self monitor. It was a battle between Abode and SimpliSafe, but simplisafe won. For it’s simplicity, flexibility, and truly was easy to install. The hardware feels cheap but it works, literally works out of the box flawlessly and that made it. Now for network, I could easily do a mesh network like google and use the ethernet ports but I would still lose a TON of download speed. Even with a direct CAT6 cable from google wifi mesh router tied to the fiber jack. Going in, I want to do it right. I obtained the Ubiquiti dream machine, along with tons of camears, two 24 port PoE ethernet switchesm 4 bay NVR, and multiple UAP-AC-Pro’s. Installation is easy, the dream machine lives up to the name with it’s built in controller for all UI based gear (protect, etc). The most difficult part is getting wires to the second story, it’s either follow up with the vents in a compliance ethernet cable, follow along in a PVC cable with the water heater, or go outside into the attic to another PoE switch if necessary for PoE powered devices. Granted, the cable would need to be outdoor rated PVC cables. My only worry is how easy it is to cut the wires. Granted I can create a sensu-esque in-house tool based on pinging a cloud device to indicate local internet access. All in all, I’ll upload pictures when the server is complete. All in all, use 5Ghz with different frequencies to prevent collision within device connection and CAT6 cables to prevent crossover.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Remillardj</name><email>hi@jremillard.com</email></author><summary type="html">Real home lab I’ve seen several posts on Hacker News regarding setting up a home lab. One thing that really itches is a standard definition of what a home lab is. Frankly, it’s too broad to have a set definition of ‘X’ amount switches, servers, and what you need to do with it. A home lab is the definition in of itself, it’s a lab. It’s a place to learn by trial and error, use new technologies.</summary></entry></feed>